lot thank you Mr
Speaker uh Mr Speaker I Rise to support
this bill also um I Rise to support the
bill because as as has been acknowledged
um across this house the bill was um was
required to consolidate the industry and
bring it under Su uh credential
supervision uh Mr Speaker it is a bill
that is part of a suite of reform that
this government this national government
has put in place to return confidence
and trust back to our Capital markets to
return
to return the confidence and trust back
to our businesses our export businesses
in particular sir this
bill replaces outdated and disjointed
legislation it fills some of the gaps
that currently exist um in the
credential regulation of this industry
and it removes some of the
inconsistencies uh that are in the
legislation for the insurance sector
what it does is in a light-handed way so
it it provides for the delivery
regulation so that we
don't mire the industry in a in a sort
of compliance mentality it focuses Mr
Speaker on licensing and credential
regulation as many of the speakers have
already alluded to um especially to it
provides for all insurers to be licensed
and supervised by The Reserve Bank and
to comply with their credential
regulations The Reserve Bank will act as
both the regulator and the
supervisor as I've already stated it's
part of a suite um to promote the sound
and efficient insurance
industry and promote confidence because
sir this year we've already provided
legislation for financial service
providers financial advisors we are
reforming Securities trustees
legislation the financial Market
Authority um that bill will be in the
house later this year sir and it is part
of a comprehensive review of Securities
markets which will be um the Securities
act in particular which will be coming
to this house later early next year the
bill covers of course a number of
categories of insurance life non-life
and medical it's
so it it did um present some issues
particularly amongst those um
non-resident
insurers um and Foreign Insurance
companies that we had to deal with in
terms of providing for a Level Playing
Field field for our local insurers which
some of the speakers have already
alluded to um and in considering those
matters I may I thank the officials some
of them are here um for the work that
they did in what is a a recently complex
area of the law and the work of the
select committee um in assessing some of
those complex
issues
we
heard about
31 submissions orally and 57 was
submitted um in written form and I
commend the industry uh for bringing a
lot of those submissions and a lot of
the issues that were contained in the uh
the the the initial bill to our
committee and the nature of their the
nature of their their submissions was
quite
comprehensive so what does it do I just
want to touch briefly on a couple of
issues um because we we will be dealing
with specific uh Clauses in the
committee stage but one was to put
outside the scope of the bill certain
types of um categories of provider and
we've already heard there were
discretionary mutuals trade associations
Union groups and and and the reason is
that they provide sort of limited
coverage which was incidental to their
primary purpose and that that's really
important we had similar carve out in
the financial services providers um
legislation which we which we which we
um dealt with earlier last month and
similarly it was important to recognize
that we don't want to over regulate
those uh Enterprises and organizations
that don't um properly fit within the
category of insurance companies we also
dealt with um the sort of smaller type
insurance companies in order that we we
limited some of the exemptions there
because we wanted to manage some of the
compliance costs that these types of
businesses uh experience there are a
whole host of other um recommendations
in our report back to the the house um
one of them was of course the Reserve
Bank would publish a list of approved
overseas Regulators for assessing home
and host regulatory recognition
treatment of branches of overseas
insurance that was particularly
important too sir sir it is a bill which
obviously has received um widespread
support across this house it's a bill
that did start under the the last
government but we are happy as a
national government to take it on and
implement it and enact this bill I
commend it to the
house word of order Chris thank you Mr
Speaker before we vote this particular
piece of legislation I I seek your
advice uh given recent announcements uh
regarding exposion within the uh labor
party caucus I want to be clear about
the numbers that will be voting on this
particular piece of legislation order
that's not a point of order the the
matter of how people cast their votes is
entirely in the hands of the whip as
that member well knows that member
responsible for making sure that he has
sufficient uh people in the house and
votes accordingly this is matter of
trust and by raising the question you
asking the question and doubting the
trust of other whips I don't think that
fits very well uh with the cover of this
place it's always been taken when the
whips speak the whips speak with honor
and I won't have anybody breach
that okay members the question is the
motion be agreed to those who of that
opinion will say I the country opinion
will say no the eyes have
it insurance itial supervision Bill
second reading this bill is set down for
committee stage next
subit exting
day I call now on government order of
the day number three interrupted debate
on the first reading of the legislation
bill